Hey guys, welcome back.
Uh, you're gonna experience something painful now, because I have no idea how to solve this mystery.
And I'm gonna keep trying to figure this out.
Maybe take it all the way back to the basics.
So, the warrior protects the chosen.
The warrior pushes back the impure.
The warrior carries the duty.
I wonder if this is some sort of... system here, where one thing weighs more than the other.
Such as the warrior is above the chosen.
The impure is below the warrior.
The wor- yeah, I don't know.
This is so confusing.
I feel like I need to solve whatever this damn word is in here.
Before I can do anything else.
This word right in front of these... is like the only thing that... is gonna pull it all together, I think.
Wait!
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
What?
Key, vessel, balance, instrument, vessel?
Wait.
Why is this showing up now?
Oh, I guess I had none of these last time I was here.
And there's five.
Oh, I swear to you, I just hit record after stopping.
I was about to spend 30 minutes on this shit.
Okay, so obviously we're onto something here.
But which one of these is it gonna be?
There's four options.
There's Duty, Sun, Moon, and Chosen.
I guess I could just try all of them.
Then again, I feel like Duty is above everything else here.
Sun, Moon, Chosen,
Duty.
Let's just try the first, see what happens.
Key, Vessel, Balance, Instrument, Vessel.
Okay.
Let's see what that does.
Oh, I see.
Uh-oh.
Oh, shit!
Okay, that was not the correct one.
Maybe it's like, okay, so the Bellman, his job is most likely to signal the whole empire here of something that is going on.
Maybe he's saying, Duty calls and call all the warriors here.
That's why they came.
Perhaps if I do this, I'm gonna call on the Chosen ones.
Oh, another thing I haven't tried yet, by the way.
I need to put on the different armor and then try and go to the Chosen ones.
And maybe they'll let me in.
Oh, I should have tried another combination.
What am I doing?
Let's see.
Chosen is Balance, Instrument, Key, Vessel, Key.
Balance,
Instrument, Key, Vessel, Key.
We're trying the Chosen ones now.
Oh, shit, I should have clicked on the thingy.
The Chosen ones.
Oh, they're just gonna keep going?
Hey, Bellman, what do you think of that?
He's gone!
Oh, shit, okay.
Let's go down.
Oh, they're all running!
I wonder what that sign is that I just did.
They're all very excited about this, apparently.
Look at that, dude!
He's special!
Still haven't understood these, though.
Are these guys gone?
They are!
Let's go!
Oh, shit, there's more!
Music, fear,
and building.
Paving the way.
Ascending?
Is that how they got up to the tower?
They ascended by building?
I think this is fear.
Music?
Build?
Well, it's kind of weird.
The way they've drawn this right here makes it seem like the instrument is smelly.
As if there's a stink to it.
Some kind of weird odor associated with it.
So now I just need to combine these.
Which one of these look the most like treasure?
This is definitely something to do with light.
It could be this, actually.
The starlight coming in like this.
Why did I write build here?
I must have done it for a good reason.
Then again, this does look like a fortification.
This does look like the beginning of this area.
Where this sign was on top, remember?
This is very similar to this picture.
Both are yelling.
Although this guy looks very scared.
This has to be fear.
This is music.
There's no doubt about it.
Is that what they maybe heard on the ship?
Perhaps they heard the music?
And that's what attracted them, not the treasure.
The soldiers came on their ship.
They heard this music from the tower.
They were enchanted by it.
Right?
Music?
No?
Okay.
Man, what could it be?
What could it be?
Do you look like anything we know?
Maybe this?
Does it look like this?
Chosen ones?
Play music on the harp.
Also, I'm not sure if that is a harp.
It's probably a different instrument.
I'm calling it a harp.
Could be singing.
Now, this is obviously treasure.
But which one of these could be treasure?
I mean, I could just combine them at this point.
I did the same thing at the end of the last chapter, so to speak, because I just could not figure it out.
I feel the same here.
I just cannot figure this out.
And I get the feeling the game has given me all the clues that it has, and I just can't do it.
I can't figure it out.
Now, whatever this is here, it's super similar to the mural, right?
And on the mural, this was not this symbol.
It was this one on the mural.
So I could just try that, you know?
That would make sense.
Now, music, though, on the other hand, I don't really have a good symbol for it anywhere.
Except maybe this guy looks like a musical instrument a little bit if you rotate this 45 degrees to the left.
You could convince me that looks like an instrument.
Nope.
Well, what else could this be other than fear?
And you know what else?
Oh, wait, wait, wait, wait, what's this?
Instrument build something.
Oh, wait, I got another one.
Oh, hold the phone.
Instrument something something.
I'm very unsure about the build part here.
Oh, wait a sec, then.
Let me look at these things again.
The chosen carries an instrument.
Yes.
I feel like it's got to be fear.
Warrior does not.
Hmm.
Man, it's got to be fear.
I just cannot imagine what else it could be, especially because this one looks like he's scared.
How is that not someone who's afraid?
Right.
Now, this symbol right here was the last word in the sentence up here, chosen once this way.
I mean, let's just try and go up, see what happens.
Oh, that's cool.
That's a great concept for an elevator.
Got the spiral.
Oh, wow.
Look at this place.
Holy shit.
OK, but I'm going to brute force this now.
I don't care.
I cannot figure it out.
This one built instrument built builds fear, maybe.
Who knows?
It's not that one.
Is this an instrument?
It is not.
Is this?
So it's none of these.
I think I got this one wrong, then.
Let's think about this.
Warrior not something death.
Warrior doesn't light death.
Does that make sense?
Warrior does not.
God damn, this is difficult.
Sun rays coming in.
Treasure.
Maybe warrior does not treasure death context, right?
Maybe the warrior does not appreciate death.
Does that make sense?
So if that's the case, this could be treasure, and this one could be the fortification.
And this one is... well, I don't know what that is, honestly.
The call of the siren that brought them here?
No.
Bro, I'm losing my mind over this.
I cannot believe that I have zero clue where to even start with these.
It's crazy.
This one I think we can pretty much confirm is this guy.
Because it's literally on the mural, right?
The music here is also on the mural.
But I think I already got that one.
So that one doesn't really count.
So it's pointing to this specifically.
Sound.
So if the chosen ones carry an instrument, what could you call the sound that they make with the instrument?
Maybe the voice of the chosen ones?
Or something?
Brother.
This thing I'm not sure about either.
Looks like an arrow pointing down.
Notice also, by the way, this one, that one, and this one are all sort of triangly.
Which leads me to believe that they all belong together.
Now,
of course I could be wrong with the starlight here.
Refraction.
Yeah, let's just brute force these three because they definitely belong together.
Starlight maybe.
And where do I have the last guy?
This here.
So that's not correct.
Let's try this combination.
Nope.
I can't wait to see what it is.
Okay.
Good.
I was right on that.
Call?
Never would have guessed that.
Never.
Now, this is fear.
100% I'm telling you.
It's fear.
This is building.
And that is... Oh, wait, wait, wait, wait.
I get it.
So the last sentence we got was, instrument builds something.
Makes music.
This is make.
Sorry, this is music.
Right?
And the build, this one is make or create.
Yeah.
Unbelievable.
Oh my God.
I would never have figured out call or treasure.
Never.
Those were not even inklings of candidate guesses in my mind.
Man, that area was tough as hell.
I could not figure out those last ones.
Jesus.
The instrument creates the music.
Exactly.
And what an area this is.
Look at this.
Oh, that is beautiful looking.
Now, the last area was cool, but I already like this way more.
I just, I prefer happier environments.
It was a little depressing last time.
So the chosen ones live here.
Does that sign say no warriors?
Oh, that looks almost Arabic.
Not that I know anything about Arabic writing, but kind of looks like it.
The chosen ones pass.
Warriors don't pass.
And this is a dot, I guess.
Okay.
All right.
Look at this.
Yeah.
That's a cool looking language.
Very nice.
Strike through.
Amazing.
So I wonder what I actually did down below when I rang the bell and all the warriors came running.
What did I signify by ringing that bell?
Maybe like the impure are coming.
Get him.
And everyone ran, you know.
Let's try and do the one to one here.
The chosen ones pass.
Oh, this is interesting.
So there is one line that connects all the different words.
So this is one sentence.
That's cool.
And there's one, two, three here as well, I think.
The chosen ones pass.
Okay.
And there's definitely a plural inside of here.
This is plural.
So we got to figure out what the plural is here.
Warriors don't pass.
Okay.
I think this is a minus in front, meaning a not.
The chosen ones pass.
And pass.
This is the sign for pass.
But wait, there's a line here too.
The chosen ones pass.
Ah, so if there's a line on each side, it means not.
I guess.
Because it's the exact same symbol, you see that?
Except this middle one, which now means warrior, instead of chosen one.
That's neat.
Okay.
So is it those two?
Those two lines?
I guess it is not.
Pass.
Go slash pass.
This is, let's see here.
I believe, is this warrior?
I forgot.
Yeah, that's warrior.
Warrior.
This one is chosen one.
Wonderful.
That guy is a little uncertain about that.
Oh, is that?
I think that's the plural sign.
Plural.
So here we're going to put plural.
Go pass is that one.
Then we have warrior, which is that one.
And this one here.
What?
Oh, not.
Wait, wait.
Not is here.
Whoops.
What did I do wrong?
Go pass is for sure that one.
Warrior.
Did I get that wrong?
Let me see.
Not.
Yeah, look at that.
Not plural.
Warrior, go pass.
Yeah.
Chosen one.
Plural pass.
Yes.
What did I do wrong here?
Maybe I got the plural wrong.
Perhaps this is actually the knot.
And these lines are the plural.
I probably mixed those two up.
Because I could see both of these being the thing.
Let's try that.
No.
Okay.
Call me intrigued then, because now I'm really not sure.
How on earth is that not correct?
Unless they're doing things in reverse.
Are they riding backwards?
No way, right?
You know what?
That would make sense, because this is quite a complicated symbol for saying plural or not.
So we have two options here.
I'm going to start with my initial sort of assessment here, where these two means not.
Looks like a minus, right?
So it makes sense to me.
And here we have two lines like that.
Then again, we also have two lines here, but you know, two lines here could mean plural.
So if we assume that and we assume backwards now, in that case, this guy would be... Ah, but does that make sense?
This guy would be plural.
Or
actually, that would make more sense as not, in my opinion.
It's a simple little symbol to make if you had to sort of specify a negative.
So not warriors pass.
So maybe this is the word for pass slash go.
And obviously, the lines here are going to be plural.
Although it could be opposite with these two.
This is just a guess at this point.
That means not warriors pass.
It's all in plural.
Then again, you want to specify a single noun to be plural in a sentence.
You don't want to specify the entire sentence to be of plural value.
Do you know what I mean?
So perhaps it is actually the other way around.
So this is not.
And this is plural.
That makes more sense to me, because you want to specify that warrior is the thing that's being pluralized.
Yeah, so here, plural chosen ones may pass.
So if we assume this is correct, let's get rid of these.
Not in this case is this.
Warrior is that guy.
I think these two are pretty much nailed.
Like that.
Oh, wait, wait, wait.
What am I doing?
Warrior.
Oh, wait a second.
What am I doing?
Go pass.
Oh, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Plural.
Okay, okay.
I somehow managed to derail my own thoughts there for a second.
So let's see.
Plural.
Yeah, yeah.
Go pass.
Not.
And warrior.
So they do do opposite.
Do do.
They read it backwards.
Incredible.
So, wait, does that mean Arabic writing is read backwards in real life too?
I don't know.
Maybe.
I don't know anything about it.
Also, it looks very Middle Eastern, doesn't it?
This whole area makes sense.
All right, let's go.
That was that was that was a challenging bit of language deciphering there.
So everything is going to be backwards.
From now on, that's going to break my brain, I think.
Look at this little funny boat here.
Huh.
Take the boat.
Oh, look at that turtles.
The chosen ones.
Hey, what's up, friendly people?
I'm not a warrior, so I'm friendly, right?
Greetings for sure.
You wouldn't start with any other word.
Or just greetings.
Greetings.
Oh,
what is he saying here?
He's I wonder if I should read it backwards, too, in the translated version above.
That's a question.
Are you a warrior?
And look, there's two dots on each side.
Could that be a question mark?
Maybe he's asking a question.
Yeah,
I think it's definitely opposite here.
I need to read this backwards.
Warrior plural.
Maybe he's asking, is that a warrior?
And then the other one's like, no, no, definitely not a warrior.
Yeah, not a warrior.
I have no clue what you're saying.
I'm sorry.
I don't speak your language yet.
I have to absorb more of it.
I apologize, but you have a very nice golden mask.
Very brilliant.
These trees are my favorite trees in the entire world.
Cipressi.
Cypress trees.
They're so cool.
I'm going to provide evidence in the comment section of this video that they are my favorite trees.
Look out for that.
Oh, hey there.
You're not going to talk to me.
Oh, my God.
Look at that.
It's flowing gold.
Oh, we got people over here, too.
Oh, hey there.
I don't know what you're saying, but your language looks so cool.
Maybe he's saying, aren't I beautiful?
Is he saying, I love myself?
He looks himself in the mirror like that.
Love.
Oh, man.
Reflection.
Me.
Look at the image for these chosen ones.
Why do they have horns?
What's up with that?
They are happy, though.
Oh, God.
I'm so overwhelmed right now.
What I need is a reset of stone.
I need a key that unlocks the whole shebang.
Someone's painting up there.
Please say I love painting.
Greetings.
Uh, chosen one.
Hmm.
Plural.
Oh, God.
Oh, you're saying so much to me.
I don't know what you're saying.
Chosen ones love to paint.
Love painting.
Yeah, I don't know what you're saying.
Sorry.
I'll be back for you.
The good news is, you're saying all the words we've heard before, because nothing new popped up.
Okay, so there's a door up there.
Let's just see what else is down here first.
Another door.
Oh, look.
Some nice pisvasa.
These people are taking golden showers.
A monkey!
Oh, my God.
What's up, monkey?
We need a key of some sort.
All right, all right.
Calm yourself.
Okay, okay.
I'll be back for that, too, I guess.
Another little monkey.
What are these guys saying?
What a nice area.
I love this place already.
This is a nice change of pace.
Okay, that guy is vibing to the music.
He loves music, right?
Greetings.
Nice playing.
I love music.
Then we have this guy, which is plural.
So, something and then something plural, something.
Isn't music great?
And then, wow, calm down there.
Man, look at this automation here.
How fancy is that?
Oh, I get it now.
Look at this mask here with the two horns.
That's what we have up in this little preview.
I see.
Okay, well, what are you saying?
It's got to be related to music.
Isn't music great?
But that's too complicated of a sentence, I think.
If
she says, I like music, it wouldn't make sense to have the plural part in the center.
It would have to be over here, before that guy.
Right?
Unless I am not supposed to read it backwards.
And what I mean by that is, the translated version above the actual text, is that in the right order?
Because if it is, then it makes sense for you to say, I love music.
Let's just assume that, actually.
Let's say this means I, or me.
I mean, we have nothing to lose here, right?
We have nothing else to go on.
Me.
It's not this guy, it is that guy.
Love.
Slash like.
Music.
Which is this dude.
Right?
Ah, but wait, now we gotta turn our brains around again.
We gotta change this up.
It's the other way.
Shit.
This is me.
Oh my goodness.
Ah, but that doesn't make sense now, actually.
Oh my god, I don't know.
Scratch it all.
Scratch it, scratch it, I don't know.
Take it back, we gotta find something definitive.
Yeah, get rid of this.
Oh my goodness.
I'm sorry I don't understand your language.
Okay, greetings.
That one we know.
That should be pretty safe, I think.
This could mean happiness.
Look at the happy face.
Chosen one, perhaps?
Look at the very symbolic mask with the horns or feathers.
Yo, look at this, this looks like a little demon, doesn't it?
What if the chosen ones are the demons?
Huh?
I'm uncovering a whole sinister plot here.
I'm gonna say you're a chosen one.
What are you doing right here?
Talking?
Could just be talk.
Whispering?
Well, I'm not sure which one it would be.
I don't know, I have so many options, right?
Hmm, I may have confused myself a lot here by getting all these glyphs without actually putting anything together yet.
I gotta go back to the start here.
Back to basics.
So, didn't we have a dude over here?
Let's set something.
Yeah, here we go, here we go.
So, what would they say when I arrive?
I just got off the boat.
Greetings.
Are...
Okay, so we know this means warrior.
Okay, so it is opposite.
I mean, it is in the same order, so I have to read it backwards in the translated version.
Okay, so we got that one confirmed, I guess.
Yeah, so warrior is here, right?
Which is the second word in the translated sentence.
That's good.
Are...
You a warrior?
And then the last one could be...
I don't think R is gonna be a word.
Maybe he's saying you a warrior?
You?
But I don't think A is gonna be a word either.
It's too complex, do you know what I mean?
We gotta go simpler than that.
Uh...
Hmm...
Maybe you know warrior.
You know warrior?
Plural?
Not plural, actually.
So the two dots at the end here...
I think that signifies a question mark.
So we're gonna do question...
Question mark.
Yeah.
I think that's what it means.
Greetings.
Are you a warrior, right?
Or something along those lines?
Ah, man, this is tough.
You...
What does that mean in the center?
Let's try and look at the glyphs themselves.
See if we can't decipher something from that.
So chosen one is like...
something that goes below the line.
This guy is a warrior, also goes below the line.
So specific ones like this go below the line.
I think this one is also referring to some kind of human.
Uh... like um...
You know, devotee, or preacher, or chosen one, or not chosen one, a warrior, of course, because we have those, but something along those lines.
A person.
Let's say a specific person.
I'm trying to think how I can reduce specific person, my confusion later when I look at that.
This is talk, I think, but...
Or maybe it's like a question mark, wondering.
It's like, hmm...
I'm too unsure.
I don't want to... let's try it.
No fucking way, I was right.
Ah, okay!
I was like, it does look like a question, like you're wondering, huh?
Greetings...
A bard!
What?
Oh, wait a sec...
Oh, that's funny.
So the chosen ones obviously don't call themselves the chosen ones.
That's only something the warriors do.
In their mind, they're just bards, because they play music!
Right?
I also called them musicians to begin with.
Until the warriors called them chosen ones.
But obviously they would do that, because they don't know any better, right?
They're just like, oh, music!
They must be the chosen ones, we love your music!
Alright, alright, alright, cool, cool.
So that was indeed a question.
I fucking knew it!
Warrior, a specific person.
So who would that person be?
Question...
Is this guy a warrior?
Is this man a warrior?
This is just a man.
Let's say, man.
Like a human, right?
Man slash human.
So, she's asking, is this guy a human, or is this human a warrior?
And then the other one says...
No!
No.
This man is not a warrior.
Warriors...
Something...
Wear swords, maybe?
Or carry swords?
So there's something missing on each side.
And they're not the same symbol, so it's not one of those funny ones, like a question or...
Not.
And then at the end, says...
Warrior plural.
Plural!
Okay, so wait a minute.
Plural warrior plural.
So she starts by saying...
No, this man is not a warrior.
Warriors...
Have armor, maybe?
Let me think.
What would come before warriors?
I don't know.
I mean, in this specific sentence.
And then here...
Some kind of word.
And then warriors...
I mean, they must be commenting on my appearance, I imagine.
Because if she asks...
Is this man a warrior?
And she says, no, this man is not a warrior.
Now she's gonna give a reason for why I'm not a warrior.
But that doesn't make sense to me.
How would you...
What would you put in front of the word warriors to describe appearance?
Yeah, that doesn't make sense to me.
You would have to put some kind of verb or...
Adjective in front of that?
Because warriors in the center of the sentence.
And then it also ends on a word that is plural, so it ends on a noun.
Oh, that's a tough one.
I don't know.
Well, at least I got something out of that.
It's a decent start, I guess.
Could have gone worse.
So, this person is looking at themselves in a mirror.
Yeah, old school selfie.
Non-permanent selfie.
And
you're not asking a question.
You're saying the same thing almost twice.
Beautiful, maybe?
I love me.
No, that doesn't make sense.
Let's think about this.
So, this one in the center here, this symbol or glyph, has to refer to a person.
Some kind of person.
Which person, though?
So, this is man-human, and I think it is.
Bard, warrior.
This is also a person.
What person could it be?
And she's saying it in a statement-wise.
She's not asking a question.
The middle word has to be a noun.
Of some sort, because we know it's a person.
Nah, I don't know about that one.
That one is tough.
Now, this guy is painting.
Maybe we can decipher something from that now that we have the knowledge of some words.
Greetings, ma'am.
Okay, you're saying a lot of stuff.
Question.
Ooh.
Again, they have the noun in the center.
How does that make sense?
Oh, actually, are humans...
bad?
Could be a sentence, right?
With the noun in the center.
But I don't know why she would say that.
God, this is messing up my brain trying to do this backwards.
Yeah, my brain is not equipped to deal with this right now.
It's just too much.
Keep going.
Oh, he's scaring them.
Oh, wait a minute.
Is he saying, I am impure?
I'm a monster.
I am scary.
I think the last one there, this one is...
Well, think about it.
The...
Warriors called them impure.
To me, they look like demons.
You know?
I think this means I or me.
Let's just write me.
This one, though, the center one, I don't know about that.
Let's just put am.
Oh, wait.
Me, human demon.
Maybe he says that.
Scaring them.
I'm a demon.
Rawr!
You know?
And they laugh about it.
Maybe I am scary.
Me... something... demons.
Wait, why does it say demons?
I meant to write demon.
Whoops.
Okay, let's see what we have up here.
Oh, here we go.
Oh, an object.
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Really?
That would make sense with the guy looking at himself in the mirror.
Also, look at the actual glyph here.
It looks exactly like a mirror image if you were to put a mirror...
with the horizontal axis there.
Right there.
Instrument.
It's got to be instrument.
Alright.
Slowly getting there.
Now, you... I would say a mask or a motion.
You know, like in the olden days, people on the stage of a theater would wear these...
expressive masks because...
people couldn't see their expressions from a long distance away.
Something like that, maybe.
Slash.
Expression.
Or mood.
Then again, it's smiling.
You know what?
Let's just call that a happy.
Oh, hap.
Let's just write expression with 1S.
Let's remove that actually.
Mask.
Happy.
Okay, okay, okay.
But why would they have statues here of these things?
That doesn't make any sense.
Unless these three things are the...
I don't know, three pillars of their civilization or culture.
Okay.
Oh, what's that?
A banana?
A fruit?
An eggplant?
An ant?
Either that or a...
balloon.
That is going to be a... dog soon.
Okay, so now that I think that means...
um...
mirror.
Let's see, uh...
this one down here again.
Uh, ha.
Me?
Ah, man, that's a... tough one.
I don't know.
I don't know what that means.
Wasn't there another path up here that I didn't take?
I want to go there.
Love these trees here.
Yeah, I want to go this way now.
Oh, then we're back here, okay.
Oh, another one!
Another eggplant!
But they grow on trees.
That's kind of weird.
Now I have two eggplants.
Can I give that to someone as a gift, maybe?
Greetings.
So what are you saying here?
Okay.
Question, right?
Um...
Probably asking, do you like music?
But that sentence doesn't make too much sense here.
Okay.
Chances are, if they're asking a question, they're going to be mentioning you, meaning me in this case.
Right?
Do you something?
The way she's, you know, her hand is there and stuff.
I don't know why.
It just strikes me as that.
Maybe man-human means you in this case.
And you know what?
That wouldn't make sense.
Because it's a specific type of person.
Right?
This could mean...
You, this could mean me, or opposite.
I'm going to say this means you.
And this means me.
Didn't I have another one saying me?
I think I'm wrong on that one.
Yeah, let's get rid of that.
I think that's wrong.
In this case...
Okay, so something, me, instrument.
How would that make sense?
Oh, us.
They're saying us in this case.
But... plural comes before me.
Yeah, that makes sense.
That means us.
So, us, instrument.
What word could come before that?
Or we, instrument.
I cannot think how this makes any logical sense.
Wait, wait, wait.
So, you're saying...
something?
Oh, man.
Yeah, I don't know.
I am so clueless.
It's crazy.
Music has got to be a part of this.
I think this one means music.
That one right there.
Either that or...
this one.
No, no, no.
That's instrument, of course.
Yeah.
I think that's music.
So, you, music.
I can't think of a word that comes before that.
Do you, music?
That one could work.
Like you, music?
Play you, music?
But nobody speaks like that.
What?
Do I have something for love or like at this point?
I think I do.
Oh, no, I don't.
Okay, never mind.
I think we have a love or like here.
Unless it's not directly in reverse.
Maybe the sentences are not in reverse like that.
Maybe the last or the first part of the sentence is the very last word and the rest is in the normal order.
So, for example, down here, music you like, it would actually be you like music.
You see what I mean?
Music is the last part, but the rest is sort of normal.
I don't know how to explain this.
That is like the only thing that could explain my confusion at this point.
I'm going to say this means like slash love.
Let's just do that.
This thing right here.
Love slash like.
I think I'm on to something here.
I have a feeling that the game is expecting me to know something about Arabic languages that I don't.
You know what I mean?
I have zero knowledge about those languages.
Obviously, it's not as straightforward as you think it is at first.
Oh, we have a dinner party or something.
Wine tasting committee?
Holy shit, that's a massive pitcher of wine.
I'm assuming.
Are you going to pour it?
Oh my God.
You got a lot of wine in that lady.
Here, fill it in my mouth.
Come on.
Pour it in my mouth.
Okay.
Fine.
Oh, another banana thingy.
Whatever.
Chili pepper, maybe.
I got three of them now.
Three jelly beans.
Three maggots or worms, whatever they're called.
Now, what's going on here?
Love like.
You see, it doesn't make sense to have love like at the end of a sentence.
I think I'm on to something here.
Grammatically, that makes no sense.
Yeah.
Actually, it could mean something because you could say I like jumping and the verb is at the end.
I don't fucking know.
Love like.
Bart.
You see, that would make sense.
Bart's love music.
You see that?
Warriors love swords.
Let's put that down as swords.
Or war or, you know, combat.
Something like that.
Warriors love swords.
Bart's love music.
Now, what else do we have here?
Yeah, that one I'm not sure about.
Let me look at the other monkeys now.
I'm getting somewhere with this.
Let's see here.
Me.
Okay, that doesn't make sense.
I think I got me wrong.
Okay.
Okay, that one I know I don't I don't know about that one.
Let's go for the first one.
This is without a doubt the hardest level so far, which makes sense because we're going higher.
It's getting more difficult, right?
Bart's.
Do they hate mirrors?
Maybe they carry mirrors.
Carry.
Could be the word.
Is that carry?
Let's see if that makes sense.
Warriors carry sword.
Yeah, that makes sense.
Let's get rid of combat there.
You can't carry a combat, can you?
Okay.
Warriors.
What do warriors do other than carry swords?
What do they do other than carry swords?
Not sure about that.
You know what?
Let's go back to the woman in the beginning.
Trying to determine whether or not we are a warrior.
Because if that is repeating, warriors carry swords.
I feel like this is how they distinguish me from a warrior.
Let's see if I'm right.
Yeah, see you.
Warrior.
Maybe this is our or is to be, you know.
So that's like a down.
Yeah, this makes sense.
Asking me, are you a warrior?
You.
But how would that grammatically make sense?
If this is indeed you, how would you ask this question?
You a warrior?
You are a warrior?
You wouldn't say that, would you?
Then again, these people in the game do say weird things sometimes.
So, perhaps.
Yeah, I think this may be is slash are.
So is.
Are.
That makes sense.
You is our warrior question.
And then she says.
You is are not warrior.
Yeah, see that makes sense.
Warriors love swords.
Yeah, they sure do.
Warriors are.
Warriors are what evil?
See, we don't know this word.
Warriors are.
Hmm.
What are warriors?
They are.
Very disciplined.
Warriors are stringent.
I don't know.
Oh, man.
What are warriors?
Maybe they're taller.
Scary.
Could be scary.
By the way, did I speak enough scary and stuff?
I got fear right.
Fear and scared are related, right?
I think they are scared of the warriors.
Yeah, that is definitely a warrior sign.
Or a fear sign.
I think.
Let's do fear.
Warriors are scary.
Yeah, let's just put scary as well just to, you know, make it sound better.
I think that one is.
We're getting there with that one now.
In the book, we don't have anything.
We do have this to fill out.
OK, so love like.
Let's see if we're right on that.
Boom.
Oh, you know what?
This could represent me myself.
So let's try both.
Let's try a mirror first.
Here, I would say this could also mean me, you know, like pointing to yourself.
Either that or I'm hungry.
I don't think that's the case, though.
Then again, I am carrying around weird chili bananas.
Perhaps I can feed someone chili bananas.
This is not going to be correct.
No, I don't know about that one.
Although you could look like you're kind of scared.
Is that what people do when they're scared?
They hold their tummy?
No, I don't think so.
Let's try me.
OK, so those are the logical things to try there.
Those made sense to me to try.
And you're saying, oh, me carry mirror.
That makes so much sense.
Me is mirror.
OK, that doesn't make sense.
Hold on.
Me.
You are a mirror, are you?
All right, then.
Me carry mirror.
Me are mirror.
I mean, if you're trying to say I am in the mirror, then yeah, you see yourself in the mirror.
There is a reflection of you there that is also you.
I think we may be onto something here.
I think this may be correct, but when we get the translation, it's going to make sense because it's context based, right?
All right, let's take a break here, man.
This place is difficult.
I'm going to have to spend some time wrapping my head around this place and also explore multiple areas here because I think we can get there a set of stones somewhere that will allow us to really break through.
Thanks for watching.
I'll see the next.
Bye bye.